今だ！
What you lack
やった！
is the ability to come up with
a plan of attack as you fight.
分かったぞ！
In other words, the ability to strategize.
相手が獲物を捕らえる瞬間 そこを狙うんだ！
The ability to... ...strategize.
ゼビル島　２日目 ゴンは　ついに ターゲットを 完璧に捕らえる技を身につけた
Still, the people who made this
game really were special... The game's programmed in such a way
痛っ…。 手が血だらけ。
of making him stronger.
この２日間　ずっと 竿を振りっ放しだったからな。
Yes!
でも　おかげで　獲物めがけて 飛んで来る鳥なら
I got the Marimo-chi!
百発百中で捕らえることが できるようになったよ これを応用すれば　きっと ヒソカのプレートも奪える
The ability to think on your feet is the most critical technique.
あとは ヒソカを見つけるだけだ！ あ　痛たた…。
First, get used to thinking all the time, until your thinking is tied to your reflexes.
だけど… どうやってヒソカを捜そう とにかく　勘を頼りに 歩き回ってみるしかないな。
This game is a training program
to help you achieve that. The hardest monster in this
area is the Bubble Horse.
ん？
If they clear that hurdle, they'll complete the second stage!
あっ。
Zetsu!
この蝶…
I got a Bubble Horse!
血のにおいに引かれてるんだ
Way to go. Yep!
[無線]
But Gon makes up for it with his
concentration and recovery speed.
[無線] ヒソカ　プレート取ったか？
They make a perfect team!
いいや　まだだよ。 どうせ　獲物が誰か 分からないんだろ？
Okay, we'll now begin to
work on your defense.
[無線]　いいや　いいよ。
Is that...
フッ。
That's right, Gon. This is the technique you've been using.
適当に３人　狩るから。
Ten, Zetsu, Ren, Hatsu, and Gyo
確かヒソカは 塔でケガをしてた
This gives it far greater power
than your regular attacks.
うまく行けば　ヒソカに たどり着けるかもしれない
I'm going to attack with my fist. You must block my attacks.
あっ。
You've figured it out?
If you use your aura to block normally, you'll take considerable damage. So what should you do?
こないだ 弓で　やられてた人だ
Ko against Ko. As long as you and your opponent
are similar in Nen capacity, you'll escape unscratched.
また来年　頑張ってね。
If your opponent hits you in a place
where you weren't using Ko, you'll be destroyed.
落ち着け
If you'd stopped using Ken,
your face would have been smashed. That was the power of Ko alone.
落ち着け！
When I add the speed and power
packed by a normal punch, it becomes many times stronger.
はぁ。
Even dozens of times stronger.
あとは待つ
I'll start by going slowly,
but you won't get any warning.
ヒソカが動くまで…
Keep using Ken, and try to
withstand my attacks.
あっ　ちょっと待った！ 俺だよ　俺！
Gon!
トンパ！　てめぇ　まさか！
Hmm, that was almost two minutes...
あ　待て　待て！ 落ち着けって！ あんたは 俺のターゲットじゃねえよ。
I had no idea it could be this
hard to keep up my Nen.
証拠　見せろ。 おぉ…。 ほら。
You need to be able to sustain
Ken for at least thirty minutes, or you won't stand a chance.
はぁ　念のため 捨てずに持っててよかったぜ。
Okay, we're through! Learning to use Ken!
もしかして　俺が ターゲットじゃねえだろうな。
Good, that was thirty minutes!
残念だが　違うな。
Over the past month,
you've become a lot tougher.
２４６番　ポンズか。
The number 3! Bingo! Killua was slightly faster.
えっ？　お前　誰か分かるのか？
Gon, give me a thousand push-ups.
あっ…　いや　その… 分からないというか
Okay, we'll begin actual
combat training today.
分かるチャンスに 恵まれないというか…。
Ken!
フッ　教えてやろうか。 何？
In your current state, your attack
power is 50, defense 50.
そいつの姿形　武器 得意技　弱点。
So if you fight each other while using Ken, you won't be able to deal much damage.
ただし交換条件がある。
What should you do? Use Ko!
あっ？
What if he hits you where
you aren't using Ko?
どうやら 木の実にあたったらしくてな…。
Use Gyo?
木の実ね。
Correct!
実は　立っているのが 精いっぱいなんだ。 お前さん　医者志望なんだろ？ 何か　いい薬は持ってないか？
From your current 50-50 state, at the moment of attack, you shift your fist to 70 POW, and the rest to 30 POW.
分かった！　ここで漏らすなよ！ 下痢止め　胃腸薬　他 大体のものは　揃ってるぜ。
You can use Gyo to alter your POW
depending on the situation. This is Ryu!
おぉ　ありがてぇ。 情報が先だ。
Let's get started... Right hand to 70 POW,
rest of your body to 30 POW!
わ　分かったよ…。
It doesn't have to be precise, so try it out.
女？
Left leg to 80 POW,
rest of your body to 20 POW!
俺が知る限り ４次試験まで残った
Head to 60 POW,
rest of your body to 40 POW!
２４人中５人が　武器として 何かしら薬品の類いを使う。
Do this for thirty minutes, three times a day.
ポンズも　その１人だ。
Add it to your current training menu.
あいつか…。
We'll begin sparring now.
特に　この女は 薬と名のつくものは 何でも使うぜ。
Use Ryu the way I just taught you.
You can start out slow.
しかし　使い方は単純 待ち一辺倒だ。
When you're on the defensive,
determine your opponent's attack power
待ち？
before defending with Ryu.
罠を仕掛けて　相手が　かかるのを じっと待つ方法さ。
With that said... Begin!
なるほどな。
I'll go first, then.
それ以外は取り立てて 警戒するところは　ない。
Right leg, 55 POW.
取っ組み合いに持ち込めば １００％勝てる相手だ。
Right leg, 60 POW, I think...
見つけたら　風向きと 自分の足元には　特に注意しな。
Left hand, 60 POW.
む…　向こうだって 誰かが自分を狙ってるのは
Right fist, 80 POW!
十分　承知してるだろうからな。
Left elbow, 80 POW!
く…　薬　くれ！ ＯＫ　念のため　少し下がりな。 は…　早く！　も…　漏れちまう！
If they keep this up daily, for two months, they'll be able to fight at
full speed while using Ryu.
あっ。
After that, it'll be time for the final stage.
フフフ…。
Time for a break! Thank you very much!
プレート　ゲット。
Osu! It's been two weeks.
やはりプレートは カバンの中か。
They've made a lot of progress...
その通り　薬は　いらないぜ ちゃんと持ってるし！
It appears you're ready for the final stage. The final stage? Yes, you will begin training in
the individual categories.
種明かしすると
3!
俺様のターゲットは お前さんなんだよ。
Bingo! A draw.
じゃ　さっき見せた札は…。
You're free to train solely in your own category.
トンパのは　これ 単に　札を取り換えただけ。
In the case of an Enhancer... You'd want to focus on your Enhancer skills, while training the nearby categories
子供騙しに引っかかったね！
of Transmuter and Emitter in a balanced fashion.
というわけだ！　アハハハ…！
Then you'll master your own category faster. 9! Bingo! A draw.
おのれ！
Good job, Killua.
てめぇは許さねえ！ おっとと…。
Same to you. Then, let's get started. Osu!
トンパ　例の場所で落ち合おう！ あいよ！
Today, we'll be training in
the Enhancer category. Level 1 is smashing rocks.
おいおい　プレートは あっちが持ってんだぜ。
Smash a thousand with a single stone
in a day, and you clear the level. And begin!
んだと！ 騙されるほうが悪いのさ！
This is pretty tough.
ぬが！
All I'm doing is
それに　チームプレーは ハンター試験じゃ常識だぜ！
changing the stone to 100 POW
at the moment of impact. But my Nen is weakening as I go.
えっ？
Oops, it crumbled...
おわ！
If the stone in your hand breaks, it's over.
騙すほうが悪いに決まっている。
Damn, I failed!
クラピカ。
What are you talking about?
You did well.
レオリオ　私と組まないか？
Okay! Let's do Transmuter training next.
フン！
Okay, then we'll decide
with rock-paper-scissors. The loser does a thousand push-ups!
こら！ プレートを返しやがれ！
Rock, paper, scissors! One more time! I win!
ヘヘヘ！　欲しけりゃ ここまで来てみな！
Damn! Hey, boys... Have you heard the theory that
rock-paper-scissors began in martial arts?
よし！　これで 俺のプレートは戻ったし…。
Long ago, when martial arts were mistaken
１６番と１１８番のプレートも 手に入れた。 クラピカ！　お前のターゲットが トンパだったとはな。
as purely destructive and banned as an evil art, martial artists trained by playing this game.
おかげで助かったぜ。 礼には及ばない。
And that's how rock-paper-scissors came to be.
お前が背後から攻撃された時 トンパに悟られないよう
You really are old...
私も黙っていたからな。 なぬ…。
That's it!
まぁそれは　あの程度の不意打ちを さけられないようでは
Eh? Evil Fist.
ギリギリ合格といっていいだろう。
Now, everyone.
何様だよ　お前は。 まぁ　しかし　チームで 動いたほうが便利なのは確かだ。
We have a total of 133 cards from
90 of the 100 total restricted slot cards. This is the product of your hard work.
残り４日　同盟と行くか。 うん。
You have our thanks. Of the remaining 10 cards, we've located 7.
お前はターゲットのプレートを ゲットしたから
They're as good as ours.
自分のプレートを合わせて すでに６点ってわけだ。 奪い返されたりしない限りな。
However, Tsezgerra's group has also obtained
もう１枚の１１８番は
an equal number of restricted slot cards.
お互いに １点にしかならないが…。 でも　何かの時に使えるかもな。
The final hurdle will likely be a
showdown against their group.
次は　レオリオのターゲット
But I believe we have more,
and better, spell cards!
２４６番　ポンズを捜そう。 尾行に気をつけろよ。
Gentlemen, our victory is near!
お前に言われたくないな。 はいはい　そうでしたね。
Can I say something?
はぁ…。
Don't mess with us!
試験開始から ずっと　つけて来てるけど
Stay calm and listen.
出て来いよ　遊ぼうぜ。
Good grief.
フン…。
But it isn't very strong.
さぁ　出て来なよ。
Let's start with how I set them.
あっ…。 いるんだろ？ 気づかれてた？
That was by touching the place on
the target I wanted to explode, and saying a certain keyword.
来ないなら こっちから行こうかな。
The keyword is "Bomber."
ダメか…　こうなったら イチかバチか…
Listen... Beware of the Bomber. In order to disarm the bombs, you must touch my body and say,
"I caught the Bomber."
えっ？　いつの間に？
However, I also have the Little Flower ability.
うぅ…。
You must be very careful as you
attempt to disarm the bombs.
チャンスだ！
This is the ability Countdown.
おぉ！ てや！
Then you've been waiting for
the day when all the cards
絶対にチャンスは来る
Now, I have a proposition.
ヒソカが獲物を 仕留めようとする瞬間！ うわ！
I will trade your lives for those
90 restricted slot cards.
ん？　何でだ？
If you agree, I will use an alternative method, and simultaneously disarm all the bombs.
何でヒソカは 反撃しないんだ？
Do nothing, and all of you will die
when the counter reaches zero.
だぁ！
You should discuss this amongst yourselves.
ハァ　ハァ…
I don't care who comes, but come alone.
ヒソカ…　なぜだ？
Are you insane?
なぜ　攻撃して来ない！
If we just catch you now and
disarm the bombs, it's all over.
このまま　よけてれば 君は勝手に死ぬからね。
Do you think you can escape alone?!
あ…　くっ。
Calm yourselves... If you get too excited,
the countdown will accelerate.
あっ…。 その　おびただしい数の好血蝶が
Because the counter is linked
to your heartbeat. What?
君の傷の深さを物語っている。
Book!
うぅ…！
Crap!
すでに誰かに　致命傷を 負わされてるんだろう？
I pray we meet again!
最期まで戦士たろうとする 心意気は分かるけどねぇ。
Leave
Send one target player
off the island.
[SR][NORM] Leave on! He escaped outside the game!
貴様　そこまで… そこまで理解していながら
We have to follow him... Wait! If we leave, the cards inside
our binders will vanish!
それでも　なお 私と戦ってはくれぬというのか！
Then what do we do? Calm down!
うん… 死人に興味ないんだよね。
It would be unwise to chase him down!
何？　私は　まだ…！
Have you forgotten why we teamed up? Because we aren't strong fighters!
君は　もう　死んでいるよ
Does anyone here think they're
strong enough to defeat him?
目が。
It would be impossible.
うぅ…。
Given his Nen abilities, he must be powerful.
バイバイ。 うっ…　うぅ…
If all of us attacked him together, he could use Little Flower to defeat us all.
うおぉ!!
Damn, we were so close! First, we must reach a consensus. Do we hand over the cards?
うっ！
Or do we fight?
あっ！
Please give him the cards...
ウソばっかり どうせ　こいつに
That's a surprise.
「死に行く私の最後の願いを」とか 泣きつかれたんだろ？
I was expecting Nickes to come. I'm surprised, too.
だってさ かわいそうだったから。
I didn't expect you to be alone...
どうせ　ホントに死ぬんだし。
Sub and Bara.
どうでもいい敵に　情けをかけるの やめなよ。 ヒソカだって　たまにやるだろ？
They're the other bombers. Now give me your ring.
相手に　とどめを刺さないで 帰っちゃったり。
What's wrong? I can't turn it over yet...
どうでもいい奴に興味は　ない。 今　殺しちゃ　もったいない人だけ 生かすわけ。
Actually, we still haven't reached a decision. And Nickes has requested the Breath
of Archangel card to save Jispa.
で　あいつのプレートは？
Screw that!
あっ　先に貰った。
As it stands, neither side can win this! Eh?
これで俺は６点になったから こっちは　いらないや　あげるよ。
You don't realize how hysterical they are.
これ　誰の？
If they can't make a decision before
time expires and they explode, you'll lose the data in their rings!
すぐ殺しちゃった。
Are you trying to bargain with me?
さて。
When striking a bargain, you have to demonstrate just
how calm and insane you are.
あっ…。
W-Wait... If you kill me...
カタカタカタ… うん　何度見ても面白い。
Don't worry. If you kill a player outside the
game and take their ring, the restricted slot data will not vanish.
やってるほうは 結構　辛いんだよね。
Well, I doubt you have any of the cards.
じゃ　俺　リミットの日まで 寝るから　頑張ってね。
Puhat! You won't get another chance.
すっかり日が暮れたな。
There are three of us.
油断しないことだ。 夜こそ　ターゲットを狙う チャンスだからな。
Well, Genthru's the main one, and we're just extras.
分かってるよ。
When the three of us join our
right thumbs and say the keyword, the bombs will be destroyed.
さて　あと２点…。
That's the alternative method.
そろそろ狩ろうかな。
Whatever... I'll take my time returning
via normal means.
今度こそ…。
You guys will be dead soon. Wait! Hold on!
ん？
Twelve hours before Genthru
revealed himself as the Bomber, a single boat attempted to
invade from the outside.
見つけた。
So it does exist in the real world.
クラピカとレオリオを狙う ヒソカ
That's gotta be Greed Island.